...an army of one.
The Outlaw Josey Wales is a western film directed by Clint Eastwood.
After avenging his family's brutal murder, Wales
is pursued by a pack of soldiers.
He prefers to travel alone, but ragtag outcasts are drawn to him - and
Wales can't bring himself to leave them unprotected.
Josey Wales, played by Clint Eastwood.
Lone Watie, played by Chief Dan George.
Laura Lee, played by Sondra Locke.
Terrill, played by Bill McKinney.
Fletcher, played by John Vernon.
Grandma Sarah, played by Paula Trueman.
The Outlaw Josey Wales is a 1976 American revisionist Western
film set during and after the American Civil War.
It was directed by and starred Clint Eastwood (as Josey Wales), with Chief
Dan George, Sondra Locke, Bill McKinney, and John Vernon.
During the Civil War, Josey Wales is a Missouri farmer turned soldier, who seeks to
avenge the death of his family and gains a reputation as a feared gunfighter.
At the end of the war, his group surrenders, but is massacred, and Wales
becomes an outlaw, pursued by bounty hunters and soldiers.
The film was adapted by Sonia Chernus and Philip Kaufman from author Asa Earl "Forrest" Carter's 1972 novel The
Rebel Outlaw: Josey Wales (republished, as shown in the movie's opening credits, as Gone to Texas).
The film was a commercial success, earning $31.8
million against a $3.7 million budget.
In 1996, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
Josey Wales was portrayed by Michael Parks in the film's
1986 sequel, The Return of Josey Wales.
His wife Laura Lee was played by Mary Ann Averett in the sequel.
The film explores themes of showdown, loss of loved
one, texas, settler, native american.
The tone is dark.